Anthony Oliver

 ♥ Marquette, MI
 ☑ anthony.m.oliver@gmail.com
 𝚱 anthonymoliver.com
 in anthonyoliver

xamox

About

I have worked in various areas of software development (full stack), including co-founding a venture-backed startup, obtaining a patent, and authoring a technical book. My experience spans from vision-guided robotics to GIS for the Michigan Department of Transportation. I've also collaborated with a Michigan Technological University professor and co-founded a company. I worked for Google as part of the Summer of Code program. I am committed to continuous learning in tech (LLMs, ML, Cloud, Security), maintain a homelab, and enjoy tinkering with tech projects in my spare time.

Highlights _____

- Startup Co-founder (Venture Backed Multiple Rounds): Sight Machine 🗹
- Patent #9955123: Machine-vision system and method for remote quality inspection of a product 🗹
- CKA: Certified Kubernetes Administrator
- Author of Computer Vision book on Oreily: Practical Computer Vision with SimpleCV
- Main contributor on open source project with thousands of users: SimpleCV
- Moderator of subreddit with over 14,000+ users
- Have worked in all major cloud venders (AWS, GCP, Azure, IBM)
- Helped Company obtain SOC2 Compliance

Education

BS Michigan Technological University - Software Engineering Sept 2001 - Dec 2006

- President local Association of Computing Machinery (ACM) Chapter
- Member of the Linux Users Group (LUG)
- · Focus: Robotics and Manufacturing

Experience _____

HERE Technologies - Lead Devops Engineer

• Implemented DevOps best practices, streamlining deployment processes across cross-functional teams.

· Developed an automated deployment tool featuring testing, rollback, semantic version control, and release notes.

- Led cost reduction initiatives, optimizing team setups and reducing organizational spend.
- Established and maintained DevOps and security standards organization-wide.

Sysdig - Senior Infrastructure Engineer

- Maintained AWS and IBM Cloud environments within the Cloud Infrastructure team.
- Automated and supported Kubernetes clusters, managing underlying VMs, storage, and databases.
- Served as a Site Reliability Engineer (SRE), supporting thousands of customers oncall.
- Managed infrastructure for monitoring and supporting other companies systems.

Sight Machine - Co-Founder / Lead DevOps Engineer

Scaled company from 2 to over 100 employees, developing software running 24/7

Remote Oct 2020 - Apr 2021

Apr 2021 - present

Remote

Ann Arbor, MI / Remote Apr 2011 - Oct 2020 at Fortune 500 companies.

- Managed Kubernetes (since v1.5) in AWS, GCP, and Azure production environments with advanced configurations.
- Achieved SOC2 compliance and executed seamless customer migrations across AWS, GCP, and Azure.
- Created in-house tools for development and deployment, and engineered fullstack solutions for edge device configuration.
- Supported legacy vision system customer with custom solutions during company transition to manufacturing analytics.
- Built a real-time vision inspection system for Chrysler, outperforming systems in 11 manufacturing plants.

Switchback - Web Developer

Ann Arbor, MI Nov 2010 – Apr 2011

CEC Controls - Vision System Engineer

Wixom, MI Apr 2008 – Oct 2010

Applied Manufacturing Technologies - Robotics Engineer

Wixom, MI

Apr 2008 – Oct 2010

Google - Summer of Code Student

Remote June 2007 – Aug 2007

Volunteer ___

A2Geeks Non-Profit

- Helped incorporate 501(c)3 non-profit for the benefit of the local community
- Helped organize and execute local events (makerfaire, ignite talks, etc

Google Summer of Code

Mentor

 Helped students develop their skills and work on an open source project, went on to Facebook/Booking.com

Technologies _

DevOps Tools: Kubernetes, Docker, CDK, Ansible, Chef, ArgoCD, Terraform, Elasticsearch, Kibana, Prometheus, Grafana, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Sentry, Sysdig, Helm, Helmfile, Fluentd, GitOps, Jenkins, StackStorm, CircleCI, TravisCI, PagerDuty, OpsGenie, Packer, Telepresence, Velero, JFrog, Harbor

Cloud Platforms: AWS, GCP, Azure, IBM Cloud, Digital Ocean

Backend / Platform: MongoDB, Cassandra, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Redis, Python, Flask, MVC, PHP, RESTful Services

Programming Languages: Python (Master), Java (Intermediate), JavaScript (Intermediate), PHP (Intermediate), C / C++ (Intermediate), Go (Beginner)